A Guide to the William E. Elmore Papers, 1976-2006
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
William E. Elmore Papers, 1976-2006
The Library of Virginia
51370
4.275 cubic feet (10 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Andrea Enghelhardt, Gastonia, North Carolina.
Biographical Information
William Edward Elmore was born on 8 February 1925. He is the son of Charles Edward Elmore (1899-1991) and Mary Sophronia Virginia Thomas (1903-1985). He graduated from Parks Air College, and then worked as an aeronautical engineer at Lockheed Aircraft Company in Burbank, California, and later at McDonnell Aircraft Company in St. Louis. Elmore married Betty Lou Fishback (b. 1930) in St. Louis on 6 December 1952.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1976-2006, of William E. Elmore (b. 1925) of Florissant, St. Louis County, Missouri, containing genealogical research on the Elmore family, most notably the descendants of Thomas Elmore (ca. 1642-1705) of New Kent and York Counties, Virginia. The material was used to compile various "working papers" and histories, including "The Trunk of an Elmore Family Tree." The collection is divided into subject files and correspondence and source files.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Subject Files.
Series II. Correspondence and Source Files.
Contents List
- Series I. Subject Files., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 1-4)
  The subject files include notes from research visits to various courthouses in Virginia and North Carolina, chronologies and timelines of life events of various Elmore descendants, lists of correspondents and addresses, published sources, English research, and family group sheets.
  - "The American Bible of William Elmore: The Old Testament". (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - An-Nah-Wah-Kah. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arobria and Lincoln County NC. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Background. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Barbados. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Browne, Thomas. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brunswick County VA. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brunswick and Lunenburg Counties, 1991. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Caswell County NC. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cherokee Connection. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chronologies/Timelines. (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondents. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Elmer, Edward (E1345). (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Elmore, Benjamin ("Family Record and Biography"). (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Elmore, John Archer (E1343). (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "An Elmore Odyssey" - Appendices - Southside and New Kent. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - England. (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Family Group Sheets - Matthias Elmore. (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Family Group Sheets - Northern Neck. (Box 2, Folder 5-9)
  - Family Group Sheets - Unknown. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Family Memorials in Prose and Verse Including Selections From the Writings of Theo. J. Elmore and the History and Genealogy of the Elmore Family.... (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Family Trees. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Featherston (E1442). (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - File 2B. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Glatton and Winwicke. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Home to the Cockade City by M. Clifford Harrison. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
  - Huntingdonshire (H1-H11). (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Hunts...Histories, etc. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Irish Elmores. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Jefferson County TN. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Little Gidding - Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Little Gidding - Start Up. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Loudoun County VA (E1344). (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Lunenburg County VA. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Names. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Paper #2 - "The Elmores in Early North Carolina". (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Paper #3 - "Names Associated With the Early Elmores". (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Paper #4 - "The Rediscovery of John Elmore of Lunenburg County, Virginia". (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Paper #5 - "Athanasius Elmore". (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Paper #6 - "An Elmore Odyssey". (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Paper #7 - "The Elmores of St. Peter's Parish (VA) and Some Associated Families". (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Paper #8 - "Three Elmore Veterans of the Revolutionary War from Orange County NC". (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Paper #9 - "The Legend of the Eight Brothers: A Genealogy of an Elmore Family". (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Paper #10 - "Shaking the Trees in Caswell County, North Carolina: A Genealogical Study of Some Elmore Families". (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Paper #11 - "Some Early Elmores in the Northern Neck of Virginia". (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Paper #12 - "English Elmore Origins". (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Peidgree. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - St. Peter's Parish. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "Some Tarpleys of Early Virginia". (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Virginia State Library, 1982. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "The Welsh Link: A Branch of the American Thomas Family". (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Williams, Jeffrey Lewis - "Lore and Legacy". (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Series II. Chester T. Bolling Files., Extent: 13 boxes. (Box 12-23, 36)
  The Chester T. Bolling files include his research notes on the Bolling family and allied lines, and compilations by other researchers. There is also information on various Bolling family homes. The files also include correspondence while Bolling served as vice-president of the BFA. Subjects include the Association's founding and organization, business and financial matters, reunions, and genealogical inquiries. There is also a good deal of material relating to the BFA's "Benjamin File Committee," which was established in 1993 to determine the lineage and parents of Benjamin Bolling (1734-1832). Other material of note in this series are typed transcriptions of the diaries of Col. William Bolling (1777-1845) of Chesterfield and Goochland Counties, Virginia, research on and restoration of Bolling family portraits held by various institutions, an index and notes to the diaries of Robert Skipwith (1810-1904) of Goochland and Powhatan Counties, and Richmond, Virginia, and information on Melungeon history and culture.
  - Argall. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Baker. (Box 12, Folder 26-29)
  - Baker. (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
  - Baker (Harley Tucker Bowling). (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Baker, Rev. Andrew. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Bassett Library Research - Pittsylvania, Henry, and Granville Counties. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Ben Bolen Church (Trout, NC). (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Benjamin Committee. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - "Benjamin File" (For Nashville). (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Bible of Archibald Bolling. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Blair, James. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - "Blue" Bollings. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Bocetti, Billie C. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Bolen, Todd. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Bolen, Todd - Back Bible Record. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Bolin Creek (UNC-Chapel Hill). (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Bolin, Norman. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Bolling and Bowling Generations by Rufus B. Bird. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Bolling, Blair - 1838 Manuscript. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Bolling, Blair - Centre Hill Cemetery. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "The Bolling, Bowlin, Bolen Family in America Before 1800" by Todd Bolen and Lois Stange. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "The Bolling, Bowlin, Bolen Family in America Before 1800" by Todd Bolen and Lois Stange (Second Edition). (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Bolling, Clay. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Bolling, Edward (1556-1592) - Descendants. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Bolling Family Association - Directory, 1 June 1992. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - The Bolling Family: Eight Centuries of Growth - Addendum. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Bolling Family Newsletter. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - "Bolling Family Photographs" by James S. Patton. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Bolling Foundation - Financial Statement, 1995. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Bolling Hall. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Bolling Hall (Bradford, Yorkshire). (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Bolling Island. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Bolling, Samuel (Laurens, SC). (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Bolling Theatre (Norton, VA). (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Bolling, Col. William - Diaries. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Bolling, Col. William - Diaries, 1809, 1827-1828, 1836-1842 (Transcriptions). (Box 15, Folder 2-11)
  - "The Bollings of Wise County, Virginia" by W. S. Rose. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - "Both Pretty Young Men" by Chester T. Bolling. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Bowlin, Delaney. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Bowling, Darrell C. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Bowling, Harley Tucker. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Braddock, Gen. Edward - Published Sources. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Bradford Cathedral. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Brawley, Dorothy P. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Browder, Barbara H.. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Stuart E. Jr. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Carson, Dorothy. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Cedar Level. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Central Intelligence Agency. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Charlotte County VA. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Charts. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Chellowe. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Chesterfield County VA. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Christmas Gift, 1991. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - The Civil War Handbook by William H. Price. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Clippings. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Cobbs Bible Record. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Cobbs Cemetery. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1978, 1981, 1985-1988, 1990-1992. (Box 16, Folder 18-26)
  - Correspondence, 1993-2002 (January 15). (Box 17, Folder 1-12)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (January 16-October). (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence, undated. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Crigler, Cora Byers. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - DNA. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - "Doubting Thomas" by Chester Thomas Bolling. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Eldridge. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Family Group Chairmen. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - First Church of Wise County. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Flat Gap Cemetery Fund. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Flavours of Our Heritage: Four Centuries of History and Cookery by the Bolling Family Association. (Box 36, Folder n/a)
  - Gibson-Purkey-Countiss. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Golden Hills (Charlotte County, VA). (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Goochland County VA. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Halifax County VA Deed Abstracts. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Hamilton, Verta. (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Hankins, Edith Jackson. (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Henry County VA Abstracts. (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Hicks, Nancy Bowling. (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Highway Markers. (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - "History of the Bolling Family of Wise County, Virginia" by Rev. C. Glenn Bolling. (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - International Genealogical Index. (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Jago, Elizabeth Fuller. (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - James, Colin. (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Kennedy-Edwards. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Lake, Willis W. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Lake, Willis W. (Benjamin Bolling File Committee). (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Land Patents. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Lemay. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - "The Lineage of Benjamin Bolling 1734-1832" by Willis W. Lake. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Lunenburg County VA. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - McConnaughey, Gibson and Cary. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - McKelway, Bill. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - McKinley, Jill (Benjamin File Committee). (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Meek. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Melungeons. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - The Melungeons by Bonnie Ball. (Box 36, Folder n/a)
  - Melungeons: Examining an Appalachian Legend by Pat Spurlock Elder. (Box 36, Folder n/a)
  - Melungeons (Kennedy). (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - A Memoir of a Portion of the Bolling Family in England and Virginia. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Minutes - Bolling Family Association Board of Directors, 27 June 1995. (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Mytinger, Laura Dee. (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Nashville Reunion Handouts. (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Navy Separation Notice. (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - North Carolina Records. (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Northern Neck. (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Notebook. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Notebook. (Box 20, Folder 2-11)
  - "Notes on the Bolling and Short Families of Pound Valley" by Chester T. Bolling. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Notes on the Early Bollings, of Bolling" by Eleanor Blanche Tempest. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - "Of Whom I Came; From Where I Came..." Volume VI, Part I (Bolling Volume) by Zelma Wells Price. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Orange County NC. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Orange County NC. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Parish Registers. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Parks, Joseph. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Patton, James S.. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Photographs. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Pittsylvania County VA. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Pocahontas. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Pocahontas' Descendants by Stuart E. Brown, Jr. et als. (Box 36, Folder n/a)
  - Pocahontas's People: The Powhatan Indians in Virginia Through Four Centuries by Helen C. Rountree. (Box 36, Folder n/a)
  - Portrait - Capt. Bolling. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Portraits. (Box 21, Folder 9-10)
  - Powhatan Bolling vs. Powhatan Boulding. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Pratt, Annie S. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Prince Edward County VA. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Published Sources. (Box 21, Folder 14-15)
  - Randolph, Brett Jr. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Ray, Katherine P. (Benjamin Bolling Project). (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Ray, Katherine Parsons (Benjamin File Committee). (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
  - Reunion Discussion Paper,1992. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - "Robert Bolling and the Bailment of Colonel Chiswell" by J.A. Leo Lemay. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Robert Bolling Woos Anne Miller: Love and Courtship in Colonial Virginia, 1760 edited by J.A. Leo Lemay. (Box 36, Folder n/a)
  - Russell County VA Census. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - School Days of a Backwoodsman and News and Views from Bold Camp, Virginia by Daniel Bartley Hollyfield. (Box 36, Folder n/a)
  - Skipwith, Robert - Diary Index and Notes. (Box 22, Folder 7-9)
  - Slaughter. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Slaughter-Bouldin Research - Bassett Library. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Software. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Speech - "1776-10". (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Spencer. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Stabile, Susan M. - Williamsburg Talk, 25 June 1993. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Stafford County VA. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Stallard, Wilma R.. (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Stifter, Lee (Stoneman Notes). (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - "The Story of Virginia: Getting to the Sources" - Virginia Historical Society. (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - "Varina on the James". (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - The Virginia Adventure - Roanoke to Jamestowne: An Archaeological and Historical Odyssey by Ivor Noel Hume. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - The Virginia Genealogist - Index. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Wallin. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Ward. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Welsh, Jean J. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - A Williamsburg Galaxy by Burke Davis. (Box 36, Folder n/a)
  - Wills and Inventories - Virginia - Index. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Wills, Jeffrey. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Wise High School Reunion, 1 July 2000. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Wytheville Cemetery. (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Series III. Colin James Files., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 23-26)
  The Colin James files include his early research on the Bolling family for a book he intended to publish. There is correspondence and notes, as well as questionnaires completed by numerous Bolling descendants. This series also contains material James accumulated while serving on the Genealogy Committee of the BFA, including the same type of records that can be found in the lineage files, and there is also information relating to the Association's founding. Finally, this series also contains genealogical material on the Bell, Clack, Crandall, Eggleston, Feild, and Harrison families.
  - Aston. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Baker, Bolling. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Banister. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - BEBG. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - BECI (Manees/Shore). (Box 23, Folder 15-16)
  - Bell. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Bell, Gaston. (Box 23, Folder 18-19)
  - Bell, George Hugh (m. Anastasia Bolling). (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Bocetti, Billie C. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Boland, William M. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Bolen, Luther Milton. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Bolen, Phillip. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Boling, Charles Noel. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Boling, Robert Howard. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Bolling. (Box 24, Folder 6-9)
  - Bolling, A. Stuart. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Bolling, Benjamin. (Box 24, Folder 11-12)
  - Bolling, Blair Wythe. (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Bolling, Cecil. (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Bolling, Charles Lanier and Josephine Lea. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Bolling, Darrel and Jane. (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Bolling, Donny. (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Bolling, Eva. (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Bolling, Frank. (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Bolling, Jesse. (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Bolling, Michael Shad. (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Bolling, Philip. (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Bolling, Raynal Cawthorne Jr. (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Bolling, Richard F. (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Bolling, Robert H. Jr. (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Bolling, Samuel B. II. (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Bolling, Sterling Ruffin Jr. (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Bowlin, Cosmo. (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Bowlin, Lynn. (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Bowling, Harley Tucker. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Bowling, Richard D. ("Jumping Branch Dick"). (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Bowling, Rudell. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Bowling, W. Harry. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Stuart E. Jr. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Buchanan-Elmore-Regan-Robinson. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Bud. (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
  - Buffington, James Marvin. (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
  - Burkett, Sharon J. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Clack. (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Crandall. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Crandall, Katherine Bolling Elcan. (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Cross Reference. (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Darnell, Alice. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Edelen, Vivian Bounds. (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
  - Eggleston. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Family Group Chairmen. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Feild. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Goodall, Wayne Stokes. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Harrison (Maribeth Vineyard). (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Harrison, Carter Henry (1736-1793). (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Melungeons. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous - Kentucky. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous - North Carolina. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous - Tennessee. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous - Virginia. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Pasqualino, Norma. (Box 26, Folder 16)
- Series IV. Alexander R. Bolling, Jr. Files., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 27-30)
  The Alexander R. "Bud" Bolling, Jr. files include information relating to the publication of his book The Bolling Family: Eight Centuries of Growth in 1990, including book reviews, correspondence with his publisher, contracts, and book orders. Much of the material in this series, however, relates to his service as president of the BFA, and as a member of the Bolling Foundation. There is correspondence, financial information, and records related to various projects undertaken by both entities. There is also material related to a BFA trip to England in 1992 led by him to visit Bolling Hall, the ancestral home located in Bradford, Yorkshire. Other items of note in this series include information on various other Bolling homes, correspondence regarding Bolling family history and his own military service in World War II, and issues of the organization's newsletter.
  - Background Information. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographic Notes. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Bolling Foundation. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Bolling Foundation - Budget. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Bolling Foundation - Donations/Financial Information. (Box 27, Folder 5-7)
  - Bolling Foundation - Projects. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Bolling Hall (Bradford, Yorkshire). (Box 27, Folder 9-10)
  - Bolling Hall (Bradford, Yorkshire) - Ephemera. (Box 30, Folder n/a)
  - Bollingbrook - Centre Hill. (Box 27, Folder 11-12)
  - Book Reviews. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Coat of Arms. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Contracts/Orders. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1979, 1984, 1986, 1988-1991. (Box 28, Folder 4-17)
  - Correspondence,1992--1993. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - England - Background Information. (Box 29, Folder 2-4)
  - England Trip. (Box 29, Folder 5-6)
  - Kippax - Cedar Level - Bolling Hall. (Box 29, Folder 7-8)
  - Newsletters. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Petersburg VA. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - "The Story of the Bollings in England". (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Williamsburg, VA. (Box 29, Folder 12)
- Series V. Joe E. Bowling Files., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 31-33)
  The Joe E. Bowling files contain his research on the ancestors and descendants of Isham Merriman Bowling (1824-1916) of Van Buren County, Arkansas, and related lines that settled in Mississippi, Tennessee, and Texas. There is correspondence with family members and other researchers, family group sheets and pedigrees, and abstracts and copies of census records, deeds, marriage records, military and pension records, and published sources.
  - Bolling Hall. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Bouldin, Thomas. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Bowling, Alexander. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Bowling, Alexander and Lucy Ann - Gravesite. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Bowling, Burgess. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Bowling, Charles T. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Bowling Correspondence. (Box 31, Folder 7-9)
  - Bowling, Henry. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Bowling, Isham Merriman. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Bowling, John I. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Bowling, Levi. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Bowling, Mark Twain. (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Bowling, Spires. (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Bowling, Thomas Sr. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Bowling, William. (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
  - Bowling, William J. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Bowling, William Thomas. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Descendants of Williams Bowling. (Box 32, Folder 6-7)
  - Family Findings - Mid-West Tennessee Genealogical Society, (July 1973). (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - The Godspeed History of Tennessee. (Box 32, Folder n/a)
  - Marriage Records. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Military Records. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Mississippi - Marshall County. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Pocahontas. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Printed Material. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Tennessee Archives. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Tennessee - Gibson County. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Tennessee - Hardeman County. (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
  - Tennessee - Haywood County. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Tennessee - Henderson County. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Tennessee - Madison County. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - White, Minerva. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Workbook. (Box 33, Folder 12-15)
  - Yandell. (Box 33, Folder 16)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous Files., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 34-35)
  The miscellaneous files include a hard copy of a portion of the Bolling Family Association database which contains descendancy charts on Bolling family immigrants to the United States, a log of entries made into the lineage database, and a bibliography of sources. Also in this series is a copy of the 2003 BFA member resource book, various materials on Bollling and allied families, and copies of the newsletter Pocahontas Trails Quarterly covering the years 1985 to 1993.
  - "Blue" Bollings (Thomas - The Swan - 1610). (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Bolen, Edward (b. ca. 1740 Ireland) - Doris Harrison. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Bolling Family Association Database. (Box 34, Folder 3-4)
  - Cantrell, James F. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Catholic Bowlings - Maryland. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Clack. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Colclough. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Del Rubio Triplets. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Genetics and Mitochondrial DNA Testing. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Hall (Jack Dean). (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Internet Communications. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Member Resource Book - 2003 Reunion Issue. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Miscellany File 1 - Virginia Historical Society Documents. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Miscellany File 2 - Zelma Wells Price Book (pp. 91-92). (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Miscellany File 3 - Zelma Wells Price Book (pp. 65-71). (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Miscellany File 4 - Bolling and Randolph Family Portraits (William and Mary). (Box 34, Folder 17)